In the last lecture, we learned about redirect,
Son derste ynlendirme hakknda rendik.
now let me show you another usage of redirect
imdi sana birka ynlendirme kullanma iznini vereyim.
actually in the new post component. There, we probably want to redirect
Aslnda yeni post bileeninde cesaret ediyoruz muhtemelen ynlendirme yapmak istiyoruz.
once we clicked the submit button your and once we made our HTTP request. We often then want to change
Sizden gnder dmesine tkladktan ve bir kez HDP isteimizi yaptktan sonra sayfay deitirmek istemiyorsunuz
the page and not remain on that page. Using the redirect component
ve ynlendirme bileenini kullanarak o sayfada kalmamak istiyoruz.
we can easily do that,
Bunu kolayca yapabiliriz.
we can import redirect from react-router-dom just like before.
Dorudan ynlendirici ynlendirici Dom'u daha nce olduu gibi dorudan alabiliriz.
Now if we place redirect in jsx here outside of a switch statement, we always have to redirect with the
koyarsak, biz her zaman iki mlkle yeniden ynlendirme yapmak zorundayz, ancak bizden yararlanamayz.
to property though, we can't use from.
GSX'de bir switch deyiminin dna yeniden ynlendirme
So here we could redirect to /posts,
Dolaysyla buradaki eik yazlara ynlendirebiliriz.
for example. The issue with that of course is now if I save a code like this, if we click onto new post
rnein tabii bununla ilgili sorun u ki eer yeni postaya tklarsam bu gibi
we are immediately redirected back to posts because the redirect component is rendered and when whenever
kodlara kaydedecek olursak, ynlendirme bileeni ilendiinde derhal yazlara geri ynlendiriliriz
this is rendered, it redirects us,
ve ie yaratldnda bize ynlendirir.
so we have no chance of entering content.
Dolaysyla ierie girme ansmz yok.
Therefore we need to render this conditionally
Bu nedenle bunu koullu hale getirmeliyiz.
and since it's a normal component as all of js react router is, we just have to render it conditionally
tamam normal bir bileen olduundan, dier ierii koullu hale getirirken koullu hale getirmek zorundayz.
as we render any other content conditionally.
Ve bu yeniden ynlendirici ynlendiricinin
So we could add a new state here
Bu yzden burada yeni bir devlet ekleyebiliriz.
maybe submit it which initially is false which we then set to true
Belki de balangta yanltr, sonra da doruya koyduk.
once we made the HTTP request. So there I'll call setState and set submitted to true.
Bir keresinde HTP talebinde bulunduumuzda orada alkol devlet syledi ve doruya gnderildiini syledi.
Now I can use submitted to determine whether or not to render redirect,
imdi, ynlendirmeyi sunup sunmayacam belirlemek iin gnderimi kullanabilirim.
so in the render method I could have a redirect variable which is null by default.
Bylece render ynteminde varsaylan olarak null olan bir ynlendirme deikeni olabilir.
But then I check if this.state.submitted is true and if it is, then redirect is equal to that redirect
durumun doru olup olmadn kontrol ederdim ve o zaman redirect, ynlendirme bileenine eit olur ve ardndan
component, and then I return jsx which includes that redirect variable which is either null or
J'yi u an olan yeniden ynlendirme deikenini ieren X olarak dndrr veya bileeni ynlendirme yaparsnz.
redirect component.
Ancak gnderilen bu
If we save that code, we can successfully go to new post but as soon as I do submit a post and it is hitting
Veri kodunu kaydettiysek, baaryla yeni bir postaya gidebiliriz ancak bir post gnderdiinde ve
the server, I am redirected with a conditional redirect.
sunucuya basarsa, koullu yeniden ynlendirme ile ynlendiriliriz.
Now this is our way of using redirect outside of a switch statement,
imdi hangi deyim dmzda ynlendirme kullanmann bu yoludur.
not with from, but instead the conditioned just is
Thrawn'la deil, bunun yerine sadece degonditioned.
did something happen so that I want to render this component? And then we only render it when we want
Bu bileeni oluturmak istediim bir ey oldu ve daha sonra yalnzca ynlendirme yapmak istediimde
to redirect.
bunu oluturduk.
Might feel strange at first that we render a component to leave the page but this is just how it works.
lk bata, sayfay terk etmeniz iin bir bileen oluturduunuzda garip gelebilir, ancak bu nasl iledii gibi.